穿上制服，还得收拾整齐
Dress uniforms. Spit and polish.
我不知道自己还能忍受多久
I don't know how much longer I'm going to be able to stand this.
仿佛有人在掐我的脖子
I feel like my neck's in a sling.
瓦肯代表是最后一批
The Vulcans are the last group of delegates we have to pick up.
只要他们顺利上船，我们就轻松了
As soon as we get them aboard, we'll be able to relax.
算了吧，今天晚上还有个正式的接风晚宴
Sure. A formal reception tonight, 114 delegates aboard for two weeks.
这两周来陆续有114位代表登船，其中还有32位大使
Thirty-two of them ambassadors.
他们互相看不顺眼，像原始反物质堆一样敏感
Half of them mad at the other half, and the whole lot touchier
更何况这次还有柯林丹星的问题
than a raw antimatter pile over this Coridan question.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
载有沙瑞克大使一行人的穿梭机准备进场
Shuttlecraft approaching with Ambassador Sarek's party.
预计抵达时间：1分钟
Estimate arrival: One minute.
允许着陆，契科夫
Bring them aboard, Mr. Chekov.
穿梭机准备进港，礼宾队到机库甲板准备
Stand by to recover shuttlecraft. Honour guard to the Hangar Deck.
机库甲板准备就绪，机库甲板准备就绪，准备减压
Clear Hangar Deck. Clear Hangar Deck. Depressurising.
接收穿梭机
Recovering shuttlecraft.
机库甲板减压完毕
Hangar Deck pressurising.
瓦肯人怎么打招呼来的？
How does that Vulcan salute go?
这比穿制服还别扭
That hurts worse than the uniform.
詹姆士·寇克舰长
Captain James Kirk.
舰长
Captain.
我的大副，史波克中校
My first officer, Commander Spock.
对于您的到来我们感到非常荣幸，很乐意为您效劳
Vulcan honours us with your presence. We come to serve.
- 由您来接待令我们倍感荣幸，舰长 - 谢谢
- Your service honours us, captain. - Thank you.
首席医疗官，麦考伊医生
Chief Medical Officer Dr. McCoy.
- 大使 - 医生
- Ambassador. - Doctor.
我的副官，同时也是我的妻子
My aides, and she who is my wife.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
我们的荣幸，女士
Our pleasure, madam.
等您安顿好，我会带您参观我们的舰队
As soon as you're settled, I'll arrange a tour of the ship.
- 史波克先生会作为您的向导 - 舰长，请换个人做向导
- Mr. Spock will conduct you. - I prefer another guide, captain.
如您所愿，大使
As you wish, ambassador.
史波克，我们会在两小时后离开瓦肯轨道
Mr. Spock, we'll leave orbit in two hours.
要不要传送过去看你父母？
Would you care to beam down and visit your parents?
舰长
Captain,
沙瑞克大使和他的妻子就是我的父母
Ambassador Sarek and his wife are my parents.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
去发现新的世界和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：茶包泰迪
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十集
「巴别塔之旅」
舰长日志，星历3842.3
Captain's log, stardate 3842.3.
我们离开了瓦肯星
We have departed Vulcan for the neutral planetoid
启程前往代号为巴别塔的中立小行星
code-named Babel.
因为这个行星正好处于我们的星域
Since it is in our sector, the Enterprise has been assigned
进取号受命护送各联邦星系大使
to transport ambassadors of Federation planets
前往参加这个重要的会议
to this vitally important council.
会议将讨论非常复杂的政治问题
The issues of the council are politically complex.
乘客之间气氛非常紧张
The passengers, explosive.
这是轮机室
This is the Engineering section.
这里有多台设备可以作为主控台的备用系统
There are a number of emergency back-up systems for the main controls.
那边是一组中控电脑
Over here are a number of control computers.
跟人类相处这么多年，你始终没学会微笑
After all these years among humans, you still haven't learned to smile.
人类的微笑表达不了多少情绪
Humans smile with so little provocation.
你也有四年没回来看我们了
And you haven't come to see us in four years, either.
父亲与我之间的关系并没有什么改变
The situation between my father and myself has not changed.
夫人，请过来
My wife, attend.
史波克先生，可以请你过来一下吗？
Mr. Spock. A moment, if you please.
是的，舰长？
Yes, captain?
请解释一下计算机的组成
Explain the computer components.
舰长，是我给史波克上的计算机启蒙教育
I gave Spock his first instruction in computers, captain.
他没有用这些知识回报瓦肯星科学研究会
He chose to devote his knowledge to Starfleet
而是选择把它们奉献给星际舰队
instead of the Vulcan Science Academy.
如果你不介意的话，舰长
If you will excuse me, captain.
大使先生，很抱歉，我不是故意要冒犯你，我是想
I'm sorry, ambassador. I did not mean to offend. I thought...
冒犯是人类的情感，舰长
Offence is a human emotion, captain.
我准备返回我的休息室
I'm returning to my quarters.
请代我继续，夫人
Continue, my wife.
沙瑞克夫人，我不太明白
Mrs. Sarek, I just don't understand.
叫我阿曼达
Amanda.
你恐怕不会念我的瓦肯星名字
I'm afraid you couldn't pronounce the Vulcan name.
你能念出来吗？
Can you?
在练习多年后只能算是勉强会念了
Well, after a fashion and after many years of practise.
我们能继续参观吗？我丈夫希望我能继续看看
Shall we continue the tour? My husband did request it.
但是听上去更像是个命令
It sounded more like a command.
是这样的，他是瓦肯人，我是他的妻子
Of course. He's a Vulcan. I'm his wife.
史波克是他的儿子
And Spock is his son.
你不能理解，舰长，瓦肯人做事要遵从逻辑
You don't understand the Vulcan way, captain. It's logical.
这比我们感情用事要好，但却并不容易做到
It's a better way than ours. But it's not easy.
史波克和沙瑞克已经有18年
It has kept Spock and Sarek from speaking as father and son
没像人类父子那样对话了
for 18 years.
史波克是我最好的大副
Spock is my best officer.
也是我的朋友
And my friend.
我很高兴他有你这样的朋友
I'm glad he has such a friend.
这对史波克来说非常不容易
It hasn't been easy on Spock.
既不是人类，也不是瓦肯星人
Neither human nor Vulcan.
除了星际舰队，他找不到其他的归属
At home nowhere, except Starfleet.
我明白了
I take it that
这也是史波克在工作问题上违逆他父亲的原因
Spock disagreed with his father on the choice of career.
我的丈夫并不反感星际舰队
My husband has nothing against Starfleet.
但是瓦肯人认为，和平不应该依靠武力来获得
But Vulcans believe that peace should not depend on force.
星际舰队只有迫不得已才使用武力
Starfleet force is used only as a last resort.
我们也是文明社会
We're an instrument of civilisation.
星际舰队对于一个想要研究宇宙的科学家而言
And it's a better opportunity for a scientist to study the universe
确实比瓦肯星科学院要更生动
than he could get at the Vulcan Science Academy.
也许吧
Perhaps.
但是沙瑞克希望史波克能够遵从他的教导
But Sarek wanted Spock to follow his teachings
就像沙瑞克当年遵从他父亲教导一样
as Sarek followed the teachings of his own father.
他们都很固执
They're both stubborn.
人之本性，舰长
A human trait, captain.
- 舰桥呼叫寇克舰长 - 不好意思
- Bridge to Captain Kirk. - Excuse me.
寇克
Kirk here.
舰长，我接收到一些信号
Captain, I picked up some sort of signal.
只是一些符号，没有确切的意义
Just a few symbols, nothing intelligible.
来源？
Source?
这也是我觉得诡异的，先生，没办法予以定位
That's what bothers me, sir. Impossible to locate.
接收到的信号量不够
There wasn't enough of it.
感应器在那一区域没有检测到任何物质
Sensors show nothing in the area.
但信号很强烈，说明信号源离我们很近
But it was a strong signal, as though it was very close.
进入四级警戒
Go to Alert Status Four.
启动远程扫描，完毕
Begin long-range scanning. Kirk out.
舰长日志，星历3842.4
Captain's log, stardate 3842.4.
这次星际大会将会讨论
The Interplanetary Conference will consider the petition
是否考虑接受柯林丹星加入联邦
of the Coridan Planets to be admitted to the Federation.
而在柯林丹星系中
The Coridan system has been claimed
有些种族的代表已经登上了进取号
by some of the races now aboard our ship as delegates,
这些代表因为一些私人原因
races who have strong personal reasons
强烈反对柯林丹星加入联邦
for keeping Coridan out of the Federation.
而目前进取号所面临的紧要问题
The most pressing problem aboard the Enterprise is to make sure
就是在大会召开前
that open warfare does not break out among the delegates
让登船的各方代表保持理智冷静
before the conference begins.
大使先生，我知道
Mr. Ambassador, I understand you had retired
在这次会议召开以前您已经卸任了
before this conference was called.
请原谅我的好奇，但是作为一个医生
Forgive my curiosity, but, as a doctor, I'm interested in Vulcan physiology.
我对瓦肯人的生理机能很感兴趣
瓦肯人在您这个年龄就选择卸任是不太常见的
Isn't it unusual for a Vulcan to retire at your age?
毕竟您才仅仅102岁
After all, you're only 102.
按照你们的纪年法算
102.437 precisely, doctor.
确切的说是102.437岁，医生
Measured in your years.
我是因为其他的原因
I had other concerns.
大使？
Ambassador?
瓦肯星的沙瑞克
Sarek of Vulcan.
你会投票同意柯林丹星加入联邦吗？
Do you vote to admit Coridan to the Federation?
伽夫大使，投票不是在这儿举行的
The vote will not be taken here, Ambassador Gav.
您将在巴比伦星的议会大厅里
My government's instructions will be heard
听到我们政府对此事的表态
in the Council Chambers on Babel.
不，我问你，你会赞成还是反对，瓦肯星的沙瑞克
No. You. How do you vote, Sarek of Vulcan?
泰勒莱特，你为什么非要知道？
Why must you know, Tellarite?
在议会里，他的投票是风向标
In council, his vote carries others.
我需要知道他给哪方投票
I will know where he stands...
以及这背后的原因
...and why.
泰勒莱特人的争论都是无缘由的，为了争论而争论
Tellarites do not argue for reasons. They simply argue.
- 不，我问的是你 - 先生们
- No. You... - Gentlemen.
沙瑞克大使先生说的非常对
Ambassador Sarek is quite correct when he points out
这里不是巴比伦星的议会大厅
this is not the Council Chamber of Babel.
我知道柯林丹星问题非常有争议
I'm fully aware that the admission of Coridan is a highly debatable issue,
但是你不可能在这儿解决问题
but you won't solve it here.
舰长，你说的对，非常有逻辑性
You are correct, captain. Quite logical.
我很抱歉，舰长
My apologies, captain.
不好意思了
You will excuse me.
大使先生您之前见过伽夫？
Have you met Gav before, ambassador?
在我上次参加一会的时候我们有过争论
We debated during my last Council session.
- 大使先生 - 伽夫大使争输了
- Ambassador. - Ambassador Gav lost.
史波克，我一直怀疑
Spock, I've always suspected
你其实比你表现出来的更人性化一些
that you were a little more human than you let on.
沙瑞克女士
Mrs. Sarek,
我知道对于瓦肯的年轻人有着极其严格的训练
I know about the rigorous training of the Vulcan youth,
但是他有没有像人类小孩儿一样四处瞎玩儿
but tell me, did he ever run and play like the human children, even in secret?
哪怕是偷偷的？
那个，他吧…
Well, he...
他曾经养过一只塞拉当宠物，而且非常喜欢它
He did have a pet sehlat he was very fond of.
塞拉？
Sehlat?
就像一只胖嘟嘟的泰迪熊
It's sort of a fat teddy bear.
一只泰迪熊？
A teddy bear?
医生，不好意思，今天对我夫人来说太过劳累了
Excuse me, doctor. It has been a rather long day for my wife.
- 舰长 - 大使
- Captain. - Ambassador.
一个泰迪熊
A teddy bear.
这么形容并不准确，医生
Not precisely, doctor.
在瓦肯星，这只所谓的泰迪熊是活的
On Vulcan, the teddy bears are alive,
而且有着六英寸的獠牙
and they have six-inch fangs.
舰桥呼叫寇克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
寇克
Kirk here.
感应器收到信号，有不明飞行物正在接近我们
Sensors are registering an unidentified vessel pacing us.
马上到
On my way.
所有值班人员进入黄色警戒，别惊扰了乘客，完毕
All duty personnel on yellow alert. Don't alarm the passengers. Kirk out.
报告
Report.
一艘小型飞船，舰长，已经尾随我们飞了5分钟了
A small ship, captain. It's been there five minutes,
始终在相位炮射程范围之外，处在感应器临界值附近
remaining outside phaser range at extreme limit of sensors.
史波克，身份确认？
Identification, Spock?
感应器信号显示这是一艘侦查舰
Sensors indicate the size of a scout ship,
但是结构与众不同，情况不寻常
but the configuration is unfamiliar. Most unusual.
对呼叫有回应吗？
Does she answer a hail?
我试过所有的频率，以及宇宙翻译器
I've tried all frequencies and hooked in the universal translator.
- 始终没有回应，长官 - 继续用翻译器呼叫
- No response, sir. - Maintain translator broadcast.
确认其是否为联邦授权航空器
Check records for authorised ships.
星际舰队确认在这个星象中，只有我们是授权船只
Starfleet records no authorised vessel in this quadrant except ours.
- 你想猜猜这艘船是什么人的吗？ - 猜猜？舰长
- Care to guess what she is? - Guess, captain?
我需要更多的数据来完成预估
I shall need more data for my estimate.
契科夫，设定航线准备拦截这艘船舰
Mr. Chekov, plot a course to intercept that vessel.
我要近距离看看她长什么样
I want to see what she looks like close up.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
你今天晚上让史波克很尴尬
You embarrassed Spock this evening.
作为一个母亲不应该这么做，他是个瓦肯人
Not even a mother may do that. He is a Vulcan.
他也是人类
He's also human.
他是星际舰队的大副
He's a Starfleet officer.
我以为你反对他参加星际舰队
I thought you didn't approve of Starfleet.
这不是关于我允许他参加舰队的问题
It is not a question of approval.
事实是，他已经是星际舰队的成员了
The fact exists. He is in Starfleet.
为了更好的建立威信，他需要被人敬仰
He must command respect if he is to function.
沙瑞克，你为他感到骄傲，是不是？
Sarek, you're proud of him, aren't you?
你现在对你儿子感到自豪，就像个人类
You're showing almost human pride in your son.
这个与骄傲自豪无关
It does not require pride
史波克应该受到他应得的尊重
to ask that Spock be given the respect which is his due.
不是因为他是我儿子，而是因为他是史波克
Not as my son, but as Spock.
你能明白吗？
Do you understand?
不完全理解，但是，没关系的
Not really. But, it doesn't matter.
反正我爱你
I love you anyway.
我知道，这么说不合逻辑
I know. It isn't logical.
船舰改变航线，并且正以曲速驶来
Vessel changing course. Heading toward us at high warp speed.
主相位炮准备
Ready main phasers.
相位炮准备就绪，长官
Phasers armed and ready, sir.
有意思
Interesting.
他们的速度几乎达到了曲速10
They were travelling at approximately warp 10.
返回原来航向，契科夫随时汇报入侵者行动
Back on original course, Mr. Chekov. Report on intruder's movements.
舰长
Captain.
舰队收到我们这边的情况汇报
Starfleet acknowledges report on our situation and confirms.
经确认，这个星象中没有联邦授权的飞行器
No authorised Federation vessel in this quadrant.
返回原始航线，舰长
Back on original heading, captain.
入侵者也随即改变了他们航线
The intruder changed course immediately after we did.
- 又开始尾随我们飞行了 - 如影随形
- It's paralleling us again. - Well, we have a shadow.
速度更快，灵活性更高，并且不可识别
Faster, more manoeuvrable, and unidentified.
史波克，全面分析感应器数据
Mr. Spock, full analysis of sensor readings.
我要知道这个入侵者是谁
I want to know who that intruder is.
瓦肯人，我要跟你谈谈
Vulcan, I would speak to you.
看上去这场谈话是无法避免了
It does seem unavoidable.
对于柯林丹星的提议你会怎么投票？
How do you vote on the Coridan admission?
大使先生，你看上去等不及会议召开了
You seem unwilling to wait for the Council meeting, ambassador.
没关系
No matter.
- 我们投赞成票 - 赞成？为什么？
- We favour admission. - You favour? Why?
根据联邦法律，柯林丹星理应得到庇护
Under Federation law, Coridan can be protected
而其星球的财富也应该用于为他的子民造福
and its wealth administered for the benefit of its people.
对你们也有好处 瓦肯人对采矿不感兴趣
It's well for you. Vulcan has no mining interest.
柯林丹星有着取之不尽的双锂晶体
Coridan has nearly unlimited wealth of dilithium crystals,
但是星球本身人口稀少，无力自保
but it is underpopulated and unprotected.
这就导致了一些非法采矿
This invites illegal mining operations.
非法？你这是在指责我们喽？
Illegal. You accuse us?
有一些你们的船舰上面运载着柯林丹星的双锂晶体
Some of your ships have been carrying Coridan dilithium crystals.
你说我们是贼吗？
You call us thieves?
先生们，先生们
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
你们之间的讨论虽然是你们的事儿
Whatever arguments you have between yourself is your business.
但我的职责是维持船舰的平安
My business is running this ship. And as long as I command...
我的话就是命令
...there will be order.
- 当然，舰长 - 明白了
- Of course, captain. - Understood.
沙瑞克，你会为你刚才的诽谤付出代价的
There will be payment for your slander, Sarek.
威胁是不合逻辑的
Threats are illogical.
而报复的代价则是高昂的
And payment is usually expensive.
保安部呼叫寇克舰长
Security to Captain Kirk.
寇克
Kirk here.
乔瑟夫上尉，长官 我在11甲板，A3区域
Lieutenant Josephs, sir. I'm on Deck 11, Section A3.
我刚刚发现了一个泰勒莱特人，被谋杀了
I just found one of the Tellarites, murdered.
我认为死者是大使先生本人，长官
I think it's the ambassador himself, sir.
他是怎么死的？
How was he killed?
他的脖子被扭断了
His neck was broken.
职业杀手的作为
By an expert.
解释一下
Explain.
从伤口的情况以及位置来看
From the nature and the location of the break,
凶手下手的力度非常精准
I'd say the killer knew exactly where to apply pressure
几乎是立刻毙命的
to snap the neck instantly.
船舰上有谁有这样的背景？
Who aboard would have that knowledge?
瓦肯人
Vulcans.
在瓦肯上，这招叫塔沙亚
On Vulcan, the method is called tal-shaya.
在古代这被认为是一种仁慈的行刑方式
It was considered a merciful form of execution in ancient times.
史波克
Spock,
就在不久前
a short time ago, I broke up an argument
我打断了伽夫和你父亲的一次争执
between Gav and your father.
真的吗，舰长？
Indeed, captain?
- 有意思 - 有意思？
- Interesting. - Interesting?
史波克，你有没有意识到这会使你父亲看上去有重大嫌疑？
Spock, do you realise that makes your father the most likely suspect?
瓦肯人不赞成使用暴力
Vulcans do not approve of violence.
你是想说他不会这么做吗？
Are you saying he couldn't have done it?
不是，舰长
No, captain.
我只是想说这次没有动机的谋杀不合逻辑
I'm merely saying it would be illogical to kill without reason.
但是如果他有动机，他能做到吗？
But if he had a reason, could he have done it?
假如确实有动机，那么我父亲
If there were a reason, my father is quite capable of killing.
逻辑上和执行能力是上可以杀人的
Logically and efficiently.
沙瑞克夫人，很抱歉打扰您
Mrs. Sarek, I'm sorry to disturb you.
我必须要跟您的先生谈谈
I must speak to your husband.
他出去有一会儿了
He's been gone for some time.
独自冥想是他在退休前就有的习惯了
It's his habit to meditate in private before retiring.
史波克，出什么事儿了？
What's wrong? Spock?
舰长，你有事找我？
You want something of me, captain?
大使先生，泰勒莱特的伽夫被谋杀了
Ambassador, the Tellarite Gav has been murdered.
大使先生，他的脖子被扭断了 按照史波克的看法，手法类似于塔沙亚
His neck was broken, Mr. Ambassador, by what Spock describes as tal-shaya.
- 真的吗？有意思 - 是真的
- Indeed? Interesting. - Yeah.
大使先生，过去的一小时你在什么地方？
Ambassador, where were you during the past hour?
- 舰长，你不是要指控他？ - 母亲
- Captain, you're not accusing him..? - Mother.
从旁证看来他是合乎逻辑的嫌疑人
Only on circumstantial evidence, he is a logical suspect.
我非常赞成
I quite agree.
那么那一个小时您都在哪儿呢？
Then where were you during the hour?
我在独自冥想，舰长
In private meditation, captain.
史波克会告诉你这种冥想是一种非常私隐的行为
Spock will tell you that such meditation is a personal experience.
不能够拿出来讨论，特别是不能跟地球人讨论
Not to be discussed. Especially not with Earthmen.
这是一个非常说得过去的借口，但是大使先生
That's a very convenient excuse, ambassador, but...
沙瑞克，沙瑞克，你怎么了？
Sarek. Sarek. What's wrong?
就瓦肯人的生理结构而言不好说他到底怎么了
It's difficult to say with Vulcan physiology.
但是我确信这跟他的心血管系统有关
But I believe it's something to do with his cardiovascular system.
你能给他治疗吗？
Can you help him?
我也不确定
I don't know that yet, either.
- 史波克 - 是的，舰长
- Spock. - Yes, captain.
我在入侵船舰舰体上检测到了三钛合金
I get sensor readings of tri-tritanium from the alien ship's hull.
对于你父亲的事儿，我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your father.
是的，这对于我们这次的任务有不好的影响
Yes, it could adversely affect our mission.
你就不担心他吗？
Aren't you worried about him?
担心是人类的情感，舰长，我接受所发生的事实
Worry is a human emotion, captain. I accept what has happened.
舰体上检测到的浓度很高
The ship's hull seems to have a high density level
或者它启动了掩体从而反射了传感器信号
or is cloaked against sensor probes.
飞行器有人驾驶，但是传感器无法对种族进行解析
It is manned, but sensors cannot make out specifics.
我知道了
I see.
这不是罗姆兰人的作风
Well, the Romulans have nothing like it.
也不是联邦或者其他中立星的船舰
Certainly not the Federation or the neutral planets.
会是克林贡人吗？
What about the Klingons?
- 我认为不像他们中的任何一个 - 那么会是谁？
- I think it unlikely it is one of theirs. - Who then?
- 舰长？ - 是的
- Captain? - Yes.
我接收到了一段信号，和之前那组来源一样
I picked up the last part of a transmission just like that other one.
我用记录器进行留存，并使用定位器对信号进行锁定
I put the recorder and the directional locator on it immediately.
契科夫，定位器显示来源为方位27，坐标8
Mr. Chekov, directional locator indicates source bearing 27 mark 8.
正是那艘入侵船舰，舰长
It's the intruder ship, sir.
上尉，把数据传导给史波克进行解码
Switch recorder to Mr. Spock's station for decode, lieutenant.
舰长
Sir.
定位器显示
The directional locator indicates...
信号接收端在这艘船舰里的某处
...reception point somewhere within the body of this ship.
一个私人接收端？
A personal receiver?
船上有人和那艘飞行器进行联络
Somebody onboard is in contact with that vessel.
大概是的，舰长，但是我没法完成数据解码
Possibly, captain. But I cannot decode this transmission.
为什么不行？
Why not?
不是已知代码，没有可破译的规律
It is in no known code. There is no detectable pattern.
也没有标准参考值
No standard references apply.
从信息自身而言能找到什么线索吗？
Are any conclusions possible from the information?
不能，它不符合我们电脑中的任何一种代码
Only negative. It fits none of our computer records.
这是一种外星代码
And it is alien.
会不会是那个凶手？想在船上玩捉迷藏吗？
Murder? Somebody out there playing tag?
上尉，定位感应器改为宽波束
Lieutenant, you've got your sensor locator on a wide beam.
既然已经知道这艘船上有个接收端
We've established a receiver onboard this vessel.
那么密切监控船上的每个角落
Tighten your field to the interior of the ship.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
如果那艘外星飞行器再次开始发信号联络
If that alien vessel starts transmitting again...
我要找到究竟是谁在进取号上跟他们联络
...I want to know who onboard the Enterprise is receiving.
老骨头，他怎么样了？
Bones, how is he?
根据检测指标读数，就目前而言
As far as I can tell from instrument readings,
我们的头号嫌疑犯心脏瓣膜功能障碍
our prime suspect has a malfunction in one of the heart valves.
这类似于人类的心脏病
It's similar to a heart attack in a human.
但就瓦肯星人的生理结构，不做手术我没法给出结论
But with Vulcan physiology, it's impossible to tell without an operation.
沙瑞克夫人，他之前有过发病史吗？
Mrs. Sarek, has he had any previous attacks?
- 没有 - 有的
- No. - Yes.
发生过三次
There were three others.
我的医生给我开了苯集塞素
My physician prescribed benjisidrine for the condition.
你为什么不告诉我呢？
Why didn't you tell me?
跟你说了也无济于事
There was nothing you could have done.
大使先生
Ambassador,
你什么时候开始发病的？
when did you have these attacks?
有两次是在我们离开瓦肯星之前
Two before we left Vulcan.
第三次，几小时以前
The third, a few hours ago.
我在观测甲板上
I was on the Observation Deck.
泰勒莱特人被杀时，我其实是丧失行为能力的
When the Tellarite was murdered, I was quite incapacitated.
没有目击证人？
There were no witnesses?
没有
None.
医生，你认为需要对心脏受损实施手术吗？
Doctor, do you propose surgery for the heart defect?
我不确定，即使对人类而言这都是个大手术
I'm not sure. It's tough enough on a human.
而对于瓦肯人，哪怕是寻常的小手术都会变得极其复杂
On a Vulcan, a ordinary operation is out of the question.
为什么？
Why?
因为瓦肯星人的心脏结构
Because of the construction of the Vulcan heart.
我建议进行低温体外循环心脏手术
I'd suggest that a cryogenic open-heart procedure
是一个合乎逻辑的手术方案
would be the logical approach.
是的，无可非议
Yes. Unquestionably.
老骨头，你觉得呢？
Bones, what about it?
我很高兴还有人记得问我的意见
I'm glad somebody's asking me something around here.
他们提出的这个方案需要
Well, the procedure they're discussing would require
为病人提供大量的血液
tremendous amounts of blood for the patient.
- 医生 - 是的
- Doctor. - Yes.
我查了血库
I've checked the blood bank.
船上的瓦肯血液和血浆
There isn't enough Vulcan blood and plasma onboard
不足以支撑下这样的手术
to even begin an operation of this type.
- 船上还有其他瓦肯星人 - 我的血型是T阴型血
- There are other Vulcans aboard. - My blood type is T-negative.
在瓦肯星上都是稀有血型
Somewhat rare, even for a Vulcan.
是阿，确实不常见
Yes, I'd say that's rare.
我的血型是T阴型血，医生
My blood is T-negative, doctor.
我们对史波克先生的血液做过很多轮的监测
We've run a number of blood tests on Mr. Spock.
那不是纯瓦肯星血液
It isn't true Vulcan blood either.
里面同时含有人类血液的成分
It has human blood elements in it.
将人类血液成分筛除还是可行的
It should be possible to filter out the human factors.
你不可能提供那么大量的血液，史波克，这会要了你命的
Even you couldn't give that much blood, Spock. It would kill you.
老骨头
Bones.
沙瑞克夫人，你需要明白
Mrs. Sarek, you must understand, the chances are extremely small
找到足够T阴型血的几率非常低
to find a way to produce sufficient T-negative blood.
- 的确，我估算出的几率是 - 别说了
- Indeed. I would estimate the odds... - Please don't.
医生
Doctor.
我看过了，史波克，但这是以猎户星人为样本的
I see it, Spock, but that was Rigelian.
猎户星人的身体结构和瓦肯人非常接近
Rigelian physiology is very similar to Vulcan.
接近不等于没风险，这毕竟是试验阶段
Similar is not good enough. It's still experimental.
但是这个方法看上去可行
But it does look promising.
史波克，我们需要的是非常大量的血源
Spock, we would need such great amounts of blood
即使这个药在瓦肯人身上产生了猎户人的效果
that even if the drug worked on the Vulcans as well as a Rigelian,
对此我持保留意见
which I am doubtful,
沙瑞克的身体仍然有可能发生危险
it would still drain Sarek to a critical level.
我考虑到了安全系数很低，但是可接受
I consider the safety factor low, but acceptable.
况且我从来没给瓦肯星人做过手术
Plus the fact I've never operated on a Vulcan before.
虽然接触过解剖标本，也知道各种器官的位置
Oh, I've studied the anatomical types. I know where all the organs are.
但是这和实际手术经验差太多了
But that's a lot different from actual surgical experience.
所以即使我没有失误，那个药物也有可能会要了他命
So if I don't kill him with the operation, the drug probably will.
什么药，医生？
What drug, doctor?
我丈夫睡着了，什么药？
My husband's asleep. What drug?
一种化学试剂
A chemical stimulant to speed up reproduction
可以刺激加速血液再生，药物尚在试验阶段
and replacement of blood in the body. It's only experimental.
药物已经在参宿V星成功完成活体实验
It has been used successfully on test subjects on Rigel V.
药物会给脾脏和肝脏带来巨大的负荷
It places a tremendous strain on the spleen and the liver.
就沙瑞克的情形看，这种药物刺激可能会要了他的命
In Sarek's condition, the stimulant would kill him.
查佩尔
Miss Chapel.
上周我做过一次体检
I underwent a physical examination last week.
可以麻烦你把相关数据调出来吗？
Would you pull those records, please?
已经看过了，史波克，你非常健康
Already pulled. You're perfectly healthy, Mr. Spock.
- 你打算干吗？ - 你打算在你身上使用这个药物吗？
- What has that got to..? - You're going to use it on yourself?
加速你自己的造血功能，然后给你父亲输血？
A transfusion from you to your father?
这是唯一的解决方案
It would seem the only answer.
这会使你造成内部器官损伤，这个会是致命的
It could damage you internally. It could kill you.
史波克，我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Spock.
我不能批准这个做法
I can't sanction it.
我也拒绝这个提议，我不能让你们俩同时冒这么大风险
And I refuse to permit it. I won't risk both of you.
那么你这个决定就等于是宣判了沙瑞克的死刑
Then you automatically condemn Sarek to death.
而你，医生，已经没有比这更符合逻辑的选项了
And you, doctor, have no logical alternative, either.
如果你不做手术，沙瑞克就会死去
If you do not operate, Sarek will die.
你现在已经有了展开手术的条件
You now have the means to perform the operation.
而我自愿做一个血液捐助者
I am volunteering myself as the blood donor.
我现在回到我的工位上，有需要的话就来叫我
I will be at my station until you require me.
舰桥呼叫，史波克
Bridge. Spock.
- 史波克 - 我在5号甲板我的舱室附近
- Spock here. - I'm on Deck 5 near my quarters.
我被一个安多利人袭击了
I've been attacked by an Andorian.
保安
Security...
- 保安部 - 舰长？
- Security team. - Captain?
舰长？舰长？
Captain? Captain?
舰长日志，星历3843.4
Captain's log, stardate 3843.4.
由史波克大副任临时指挥官
First Officer Spock in temporary command.
舰长被参加巴比伦会议的一个代表袭击
The captain has been critically wounded
受了重伤
by one of the delegates to the Babel conference.
全舰警戒
The ship is on Alert Status.
入侵舰仍在尾随
We are still being followed by the intruder vessel.
伤情严重，左肺被刺穿
It's a bad wound. Punctured left lung.
再低几厘米就会伤到心脏了
Centimetre or so lower, it would have gone through the heart.
我会去禁闭室审问安多利星的那个嫌疑人
I'll be in the brig questioning the Andorian prisoner.
医生，K-2指征正在下降
Doctor, the K-2 factor is dropping.
史波克
Spock.
你父亲的情况正在恶化，现在已经没的选了
Your father is much worse. There's no longer a choice.
我必须马上为他实施手术
I have to operate immediately.
你一旦准备好了，我们就马上开始手术
We can begin as soon as you're prepared.
- 不行，医生 - 什么？
- No, doctor. - What?
根据星际舰队的规定
My first responsibility is to the ship.
现在我的首要任务是确保船舰以及乘客的安全
Our passengers' safety is, by Starfleet order, of first importance.
我们现在被一艘未知且不怀好意的船舰尾随
We are being followed by an alien, possibly hostile vessel.
我不能在这样的情况下放弃指挥权
I cannot relinquish command under these circumstances.
你可以将指挥权移交给史考特
You can turn command over to Scotty.
理由是什么，医生？
On what grounds, doctor?
个人意志应绝对服从舰队指挥
Command requirements do not recognise personal privilege.
我会去禁闭室审讯安多利星人
I will be in the brig, interrogating the Andorian.
他叫泰勒夫，我的低阶侍卫
He is Thelev, a minor member of my staff.
我只知道他工作尽职，其余的并不了解
I know nothing of him except that he has served adequately.
我们已经给他使用了测谎仪和吐真剂
He has been subjected to questioning under verifier scan and truth drug.
他并没有说出什么实质的东西
He reveals nothing.
我认为他对于整体的计划
I suggest his mind has been so conditioned
所知并不详尽
as part of a preconceived plan.
我们的族人虽然尚武
My people are a violent race,
但我们和寇克舰长并没有过节
but we had no quarrel with Captain Kirk.
- 泰勒夫显然有 - 这都是你的猜测
- Apparently Thelev did. - Suggest the plot.
伤害舰长对我们有什么好处？
How could it profit us to harm the captain?
我不知道
I do not know.
泰勒夫袭击舰长完全不符合逻辑
There is no logic in Thelev's attack upon the captain.
伽夫遇害也同样毫无逻辑可言
There is no logic in Gav's murder.
也许你应该试着不去分析逻辑
Perhaps you should forget logic.
而是从动机
Devote yourself to motivations
或者获益方面入手
of passion or gain.
这些才是通常的谋杀动机
Those are reasons for murder.
进来
Come in.
史波克，你现在必须把指挥权移交给别人
Spock, you must turn command over to somebody else.
母亲，在我加入舰队的时候曾经宣誓
When I was commissioned, I took an oath to carry out responsibilities
我将对我的职位尽忠职守
which were clearly and exactly specified.
任何有能力的人都能胜任船舰的指挥权
Any competent officer can command this ship.
但是只有你能给你父亲输血
Only you can give your father the blood transfusions
来拯救他的生命
that he needs to live.
在常态下，任何有能力的人都能胜任船舰的指挥权
Any competent officer can command this ship under normal circumstances.
但现在情况特殊
The circumstances are not normal.
船舰上现在有超过100位联邦星系重要的客人
We're carrying over 100 valuable Federation passengers.
船舰正在被一艘外来战舰尾随，随时可能受到攻击
We're being pursued by an alien ship, we're subject to possible attack.
而船上发生了谋杀以及谋杀未遂的事件
There has been murder and attempted murder onboard.
- 我不能放弃我的职责 - 职责？你的职责应该是挽救你父亲
- I cannot dismiss my duties. - Duty? Your duty is to your father.
我知道
I know.
但是现在确保船舰安全才是首要职责
But this must take precedence.
如果在不延误时间
If I could give the transfusion without loss of time or efficiency, I would.
或不影响效率的情况下可以完成输血，我很愿意
沙瑞克理解我的理由
Sarek understands my reason.
但是我不理解，这太不人性化了
Well, I don't. It's not human.
我不是要指责你，但是你也有一部分属于人类
Oh, that's not a dirty word. You're human too.
让你人类的那一半做确定好不好
Let that part of you come through.
你父亲快死了
Your father's dying.
母亲，你怎么可能在瓦肯生存这么久
Mother, how can you have lived on Vulcan so long,
与瓦肯人结婚，并生儿育女
married a Vulcan, raised a son on Vulcan,
但是却始终不明白对瓦肯人来说什么才是重要的？
without understanding what it means to be a Vulcan?
我情愿选择我不知道
Well, if this is what it means, I don't want to know.
选择遵从逻辑并且获益最大的方法
It means to adopt a philosophy, a way of life,
是瓦肯人的处世之道
which is logical and beneficial.
我们不能因为一己私欲就漠视这种处世哲学
We cannot disregard that philosophy merely for personal gain,
无论这件事有多么重要
no matter how important that gain might be.
没有什么能比你父亲的生命更重要的了
Nothing is as important as your father's life.
你觉得如果我同意了你的做法
Can you imagine what my father would say if I were to agree?
因为父亲一人的性命，从而放弃星舰指挥权
If I were to give up command of this vessel,
致上百人性命于危险之中，从而引发星系间的战争
jeopardise hundreds of lives, risk interplanetary war,
父亲会说什么？
all for the life of one person?
你5岁那年
When you were five years old
满脸伤心气愤的回到家
and came home stiff-lipped, anguished
因为其他孩子欺负你
because the other boys tormented you,
说你不是真正的瓦肯星人
saying that you weren't really Vulcan...
我看着你，知道在你身体里面
...I watched you, knowing that inside...
属于人类的那一半正在哭泣
...the human part of you was crying.
我也跟着掉了眼泪
And I cried too.
这个身体里我所赋予的那一半
There must be some part of me in you.
和我是感同身受的
Some part that I still can reach.
如果做一个真正的瓦肯星人对你来说真这么重要
If being Vulcan is more important to you,
那你就继续守在这儿
then you'll stand there...
高谈阔论那些星际舰队以及瓦肯的原则规矩哲学
...speaking rules and regulations from Starfleet and Vulcan philosophy...
然后眼睁睁的看着你父亲死去
...and let your father die.
而我，将用我的余生一直恨你
And I'll hate you for the rest of my life.
母亲
Mother...
去你父亲那儿吧，求你了
Oh, go to him now. Please.
我做不到
I cannot.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy.
我现在真想按住那个拿锤子的家伙
I'd like to get my hands on the guy with the sledgehammer.
袭击你的那个？
The one who hit you?
不是，在我脑袋里的那个
No, the one inside my head.
我昏迷了多久？
How long have l..?
能活下来就偷笑了，这是给你个教训
Now, let that be a lesson to you.
你最好还是老老实实的在床上躺着吧
Just lie there and be happy you're still alive.
沙瑞克怎么样了？
How's Sarek?
很不好，除非我能做手术
Not good. If I could only operate...
为什么还没做？
What's stopping you?
我以为已经万事俱备了
I thought you were all ready.
之前确实是，可你受伤了，史波克接管指挥权
I was. When you became injured, Spock assumed command.
他会一直坚守岗位，直到你恢复
He's going to stay there till you get back on your feet,
即使这会要了沙瑞克的命
even if it costs Sarek his life.
规章制度什么的
Regulations.
我不会因为他的尽忠职守而责备他
I can't damn him for his loyalty.
但我也不会让他因此而背负弑父的罪名
For doing his duty. But I'm not going to let him commit patricide.
吉姆，你如果起来伤口又会开始流血
Jim, if you stand, you could start to bleed again.
老骨头
Bones...
沙瑞克如果不做手术会死的
...Sarek will die without that operation.
没有史波克输血你无法完成这个手术
And you can't operate without transfusions from Spock.
我会告诉史波克我已经没事儿了
I'll convince Spock I'm all right...
然后命令他到你这儿来，等他从舰桥离开
...and order him to report here. Soon as he leaves the Bridge,
我就把指挥权交给史考特，然后回房间休息
I'll turn command over to Scotty and report to my quarters.
这也算谨遵医嘱了吧？
Will that fill your prescription?
- 舰长 - 我现在接手，史波克
- Captain. - I'll take over, Mr. Spock.
你现在跟麦考伊医生去医务室吧
You report to Sickbay with Dr. McCoy.
舰长，你确定没问题了吗？
Captain, are you quite all right?
我已经检查过，他没问题了，史波克
I've certified him physically fit, Mr. Spock.
现在我需要做个手术
Now, since I have an operation to perform,
- 咱俩都需要去 - 去吧，史波克
- and both of us are required... - Get out, Spock.
契科夫，入侵船舰现在什么情况？
Mr. Chekov, what's the status of the intruder?
没有变化，长官，与我们始终保持一定距离
No change, sir. Maintaining its distance.
还有进一步的通讯联系吗，上尉？
Any further transmissions, lieutenant?
没有，长官
None, sir.
让史考特来舰桥
Call Mr. Scott to the Bridge.
舰长，外星战舰向我方靠近
Captain, the alien vessel is moving closer.
收回刚才的指令，我继续指挥
Belay that order. I'll stay here.
舰长，我再次收到外来信号
Captain, I'm picking up the alien signal again.
但是这次是从进取号内部发出的
But it's coming from inside the Enterprise.
- 具体发射源？ - 是禁闭室，长官
- Specific origin? - From the brig, sir.
保安
Security.
保安请到禁闭室 立刻搜查嫌疑犯
Security to the brig. Search the prisoner immediately.
读数，护士
Readings, nurse.
史波克的血液再生指数已经超过200%
Mr. Spock's blood reproduction rate is up over 200 percent.
沙瑞克心跳上升到324
Sarek's heartbeat has risen to 324.
血压90/40 正在下降
Blood pressure 90/40, dropping.
真想知道这代表好还是不好
I wish I knew whether that was good or bad.
准备无菌室
Initiate sterile field.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
- 你去哪儿？ - 我需要立刻见舰长
- Where do you think you're going? - I must see the captain.
我的病人别想在手术中途四处乱跑
My patients don't walk out in the middle of an operation.
我刚意识到，那个外星船舰
The alien ship, I just realised,
如果他们的动力利用率曲线不同寻常
if their power utilisation curve is not the norm,
可以利用这个特点来确认他们的身份
it should be possible to identify them this way.
非常重要
Very important.
你父亲的命也很重要
So is your father's life.
寇克
Kirk here.
保安部，我们不得不打晕那个安多利人
Security here. We had to stun the Andorian.
他有某种通讯装置，藏匿在他的触角里面
He had some sort of transceiver. It was hidden in his antenna.
舰长，外星船舰的航线和速度发生了变化
Captain, the alien ship has changed course and speed.
以曲速8向我们冲过来了
Moving directly toward us at warp 8.
把犯人带到舰桥
Bring the prisoner to the Bridge.
启动防护罩，红色预警
Deflectors on. Red alert.
- 听我指令，相位炮准备开火 - 是，长官
- Phasers stand by to fire on my order. - Aye, sir.
防护罩启动，相位炮就绪，长官
Shields on, phasers manned and ready, sir.
- 契科夫，接管史波克的扫描器 - 是，长官
- Chekov, take over Spock's scanners. - Aye, sir.
目标，契科夫
Target, Mr. Chekov?
它离开了，正在转向，即将驶回
Moving away, turning now. He's coming around again.
过来就开火，少尉
Fire as he passes, ensign.
没打中，长官
Clean miss, sir.
契科夫，报告他的武器装备
Report on his weaponry, Mr. Chekov.
感应器显示只有标准相位炮，长官
Sensors record standard phasers, sir.
标准相位炮，很好
Standard phasers. Good.
他们速度很快，但不是不可战胜的
They have more speed, but they're not giants.
舰长，内部通讯系统阻塞
Captain, the intercoms are jammed.
所有的大使都在问怎么了
All the ambassadors are asking what's going on.
让他们自己猜猜，但是什么也别说，上尉
Tell them to take a good guess, but clear that board, lieutenant.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
它又过来了
It's coming around again.
再这么来一次这俩人我都保不住了
One more like that and I'm going to lose both these men.
武器控制系统已经锁定目标，舰长
Fire control locked into the computers, captain.
听我命令，发射2号、4号、6号光子鱼雷
On my order, fire photon torpedoes two, four, and six.
- 增大覆盖范围 - 是，长官
- Widest possible scatter. - Aye, sir.
开火
Fire.
都没打中，长官，他们的移动速度远快过我们
Full spread missed, sir. They're moving too fast for us.
- 医生，他停止心跳了 - 心脏起搏
- Doctor, his heart's stopped. - Cardiostimulate.
设备不能运转了
The systems are off.
把那套旧的便携起搏器拿来
Then get me that old portable cardiostimulator.
通知轮机室，医疗室需要优先恢复供电
Call Engineering and have Sickbay systems put on priority.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
4号护盾损坏，长官
Number four shield has buckled, sir.
- 辅助电源 - 完成切换
- Auxiliary power. - Switching over.
护盾回升
Shields firming up.
4号护盾依然薄弱，长官
Number four is still weak, sir.
如果他们再次攻击这个位置，肯定坚持不住了
If they hit us there again, it'll go altogether.
你的同伙做的不错
Your friends out there are good.
可是除非完全摧毁这艘星舰，否则他们赢不了
They'll have to destroy this ship to win.
这正是我们最开始的打算，舰长
That was intended from the beginning, captain.
你不是安多利人，你到底是什么人？
You're not Andorian. Who are you?
舰长，各层甲板都有损毁
Damage reports coming in, captain. Every deck.
所有甲板启动损毁控制程序
Damage control procedures, all decks.
那艘船有相位炮，至少武器上我们不相上下
That ship out there has phasers. At least our weapons are alike.
2号护盾损毁，长官
Number two shield is gone, sir.
轮机室，这里是舰长
Engineering. This is the captain.
切断左舷除相位炮以外的动力
Cut power on the port side except for phaser banks.
听我指令，切断右舷动力，呼叫完毕
At my signal, cut starboard power. Kirk out.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你自己琢磨吧，反正你也活不长了，舰长
Find your own answers, captain. You haven't long to live.
你是个间谍，动过手术变异乔庄成安多利人混上船
You're a spy, surgically altered to pass as an Andorian,
混进大使团内部，企图用暗杀来制造内讧
planted in the ambassador's party to use terror and murder to disrupt us,
并且帮助外星船舰进行袭击
and prepare for this attack.
都是你的臆想，舰长
Speculation, captain.
轮机室，切断右舷动力，待命
Engineering, cut power on starboard side. Maintain until further orders.
契科夫
Chekov.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
你也臆想一下
You speculate.
舰长，我们开始漂移了，需要我让舰体返回航线吗？
We're starting to drift, sir. Shall I hold her on course?
不用，准备好相位炮，契科夫
No. Stand by your phasers, Mr. Chekov.
是，长官，相位炮就绪
Aye, sir. Phasers standing by.
对方悬停了，舰长
He's just hovering out there, sir.
正在观察我们
Looking us over.
它估计觉得我们不行了
We're dead, as far as he knows.
你在放诱饵，引它们上钩
You're baiting him. You're trying to lure him in.
过来了
Here he comes.
相隔距离缩短，速度降低接近亚光速
Range decreasing. Speed dropping close to sub-light.
准备开火，契科夫
Hold your fire, Mr. Chekov.
相位炮锁定目标，距离持续缩短
Phasers locked on target. Range closing.
75000千米
Seventy-five thousand kilometres.
开火
Fire.
打中了
Got him!
解除战斗部署
Secure from general quarters.
上尉，开启呼叫频率
Lieutenant, open a hailing frequency.
如果他们要投降的话
If they wish to surrender...
他们不可能投降的，舰长
They could not surrender, captain.
他们都是死士
They had orders to self-destruct.
上尉，把情况汇报给星际舰队
Lieutenant, relay to Starfleet Command.
告诉他们我们有个在押犯
Tell them we have a prisoner.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
在押只是暂时的，舰长
Only temporarily, captain.
我也是名死士
You see, I had orders to self-destruct too.
慢性毒药
Slow poison.
几乎没有痛苦，也没有解药
Quite painless, actually, but there is no known antidote.
预计我还能再活10分钟
I anticipate another ten minutes of life.
带他去医务室
Take him to Sickbay.
我好想算错了
I seem to have miscalculated.
那些人也是
So did they.
契科夫，接替指挥
Mr. Chekov, take over.
老骨头？
Bones?
你一直让船舰摇摇晃晃来的？
Are you quite through shaking this ship around?
史波克，沙瑞克，他们怎么样？
Spock, Sarek. How are they?
我可以告诉你，你给手术的实施增加了巨大的困难
I don't mind telling you, you sure make it difficult for a surgeon trying...
- 老骨头！ - 舰长，在这边
- Bones! - Captain, come in.
多亏了瓦肯星人顽固的毅力
That pig-headed Vulcan stamina.
不然我也不能妙手回春
I couldn't have pulled them through without it.
某医生运气不错
Some doctors have all the luck.
- 舰长，我相信你能发现外星 - 我们已经摧毁了那艘船舰
- Captain, I believe you'll find the alien... - We damaged their ship.
他们启动了自毁来避免被俘
They destroyed themselves to avoid capture.
老骨头，泰勒夫的尸体会送到你的实验室
Bones, Thelev's body will be brought to your lab.
我需要你尽快为其做尸检
I want an autopsy performed as soon as possible.
我想你会发现他其实是猎户星人，医生
I think you'll find he's an Orion, doctor.
猎户星人？
Orion?
有情报指出猎户星走私者
Intelligence reports that Orion smugglers
曾经洗劫过柯林丹星系
have been raiding the Coridan system.
但是袭击星际舰队他们又能从中得到什么好处呢？
But what would they gain by an attack on Starfleet?
内讧和星际大战
Mutual suspicion and interplanetary war.
是阿，猎户星是中立的
Yes, of course. With Orion carefully neutral,
他们可以向战争双方提供双锂晶体
they'd clean up by supplying dilithium to both sides
同时继续掠夺柯林丹星的资源
and continue to raid Coridan.
之前我觉得不解的是他们的动力源曲线
The thing that confused me was the power utilisation curve.
他们比一般我们已知的星舰
It made them seem more powerful than a starship
动力更强
or anything known to us.
这艘星舰是为了执行自杀式袭击的
That ship was constructed for a suicide mission.
所以他们从没有考虑过返航
Since they never intended to return to their home base,
他们才会在袭击的时候使用全部动力
they could use 100 percent power on their attacks.
我不明白的是，我之前为什么没能早点儿意识到这个
The thing I don't understand is why I didn't think of it earlier.
因为你脑子里在想别的事儿
You might have had something else on your mind.
这不太可能
It hardly seems likely.
是阿，但是还是谢谢你了
No. But thank you anyway.
你呢，沙瑞克，你是不是也应该谢谢你儿子啊
And you, Sarek. Would you also say thank you to your son?
我不理解
I don't understand.
他救了你一命
For saving your life.
史波克只是在遵从逻辑处理
Spock acted in the only logical manner open to him.
我们不需要向逻辑道谢的，阿曼达
One does not thank logic, Amanda.
逻辑，逻辑，我受够了讨厌的逻辑了
Logic. Logic. I'm sick to death of logic.
你想知道我对你们的那些逻辑怎么想吗？
Do you want to know how I feel about your logic?
- 她是不是又情绪化了？ - 她经常这样
- Emotional, isn't she? - She has always been that way.
是吗？那你为什么还娶她？
Indeed? Why did you marry her?
那个时候，和她结成连理是非常符合逻辑的
At the time, it seemed the logical thing to do.
老骨头，没事儿没事儿，我挺好的
Bones. No, no, I'm all right.
你要是再跟我这个和善的家庭医生较劲
Now, if you keep arguing with your kindly family doctor,
我就让你在床上躺10天
you're going to spend your next ten days right here.
你要是配合，最多就躺两天
If you cooperate, you'll be out in two.
医生，我觉得我可以返回我的岗位了
Doctor, I think I'll return to my station now.
史波克，病床就是你的岗位
You are at your station, Mr. Spock.
麦考伊医生，我觉得你现在乐在其中啊
Dr. McCoy, I believe you're enjoying all this.
没错，舰长，我从没见过他这么高兴过
Indeed, captain. I've never seen him look so happy.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
哈哈，真不容易，世界终于安静了
Well, what do you know? I finally got the last word.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/